Nathaniel Johnson

Fremont, California, United States



njohnson.esquire@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/nathanieljohnson

Summary

Program manager for Meta specializing in internal product support and project analysis. Currently finishing a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp course through Berkeley Extended Education to further develop hard skills to remain agile within the evolving IT industry.

Experience



Survey Platform Operations Program Manager

Meta (Rose Intl)

Jun 2021 - Present (2 years)

Single-handedly running reactive and consultation support for the internal survey platforms for all Meta products used by thousands of Meta researchers

Executing on all SLAs related to Survey Platform Operations

Administrator on call for all researchers and engineers utilizing internal surveying tools

Subject Matter Expert for tooling setup including pre and post launch surveying and triaging survey diagnostics

Deep-diving into survey analytics using PostgreSQL databases

Presenting and analyzing quarterly review targets making use of organizational schema I personally adapted and refined in order to highlight trends in the support group I lead

Collaboration with internationally-based engineering team for escalations and backlog feature submissions



Technical Account Manager

Google (ICONMA)

Nov 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Supported and consulted for merchants and business partners in the online retail commerce space to cultivate, understand and integrate data with Google Shopping Actions

Provided high touch consulting and technical support to anchor and strategic merchant partners to ensure smooth data integration and increase success on Google Shopping platform

Managed direct relationship with up to 30 merchant accounts concurrently, acting as point of contact within Google Shopping organization in order to provide full life-cycle support to established merchants Identified opportunities to grow business sales through platform optimization to increase revenue.

Troubleshooted, escalated and responded to product support requests from merchants and third-party channel partners and worked with internal cross-functional teams to deliver results within SLA and KPI requirements

Leveraged Google Merchant Center, Gearloose 2.0, Salesforce, Excel, Tableau, Google Suite, Bug Tracker internal tools, and various logs and data to identify and troubleshoot merchant issues while recommending solutions

Crafted PLX scripts and SQL queries to compile, analyze and deliver reports on relevant partner data Assisted in the training of peers to onboard efficiently into growing team

Created client monitoring and operational tools and tracking applications including account plans

Reviewed, edited, and revised both internal and external technical articles for Merchant Center Help Center for new Google Shopping features and updates for scaled support teams

Troubleshot fulfillment and data bugs for support team and partner managers seeking to better understand client sales and retailer standards data

Reviewed appeals from merchants and account managers to examine account-impacting performance standards

Remained agile to tackle ad hoc consulting and data analysis for top tier clients and program managers Audited merchant support for new vendors to transition scaled support model

Marketing Platforms Consultant

Better Body Work

Aug 2019 - Oct 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Provide Subject Matter Expertise on promoted growth of marketing strategies within Instagram and Facebook advertising ecosystems

Develop SOPs and guided resources for network of posters to build out visibility of organic social network growth

Troubleshoot advertising bugs and ad hoc issues on Facebook ad platforms

Provide walkthroughs and best practices of Facebook Ads Manager, Business Manager and Instagram's internal paid promotion system to drive traffic on all parent and associated BBW and related accounts



FB) Business Product Support Analyst II

Facebook

May 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Handled and assessed product issues as they related to Instagram advertising platforms Collaborated with support team to identify platform bugs, offer solutions and escalate to engineering as necessary

Utilized internal tools in order to replicate and identify client usage patterns

Assuaged client concerns and manage expectations of client accounts to ensure positive relationship between partners

Trained and onboarded new members of the team to handle job performance tasks and SLAs

Managed workflows and kept up with SLAs as designated to meet client needs

Tackled KPI metrics and followed multiple Tableaux organizational dashboards as a driving member of a close-knit collaborative team

Received & published questions in knowledge base hub for concierge business filers and other Facebook employees

Monitored incoming communications from top tier clients in order to increase process efficiency Published and develop the Product Support Team's newsletter

Ran BPS team events as coordinator on the Events & Engagement Committee



Online Quality Training Specialist

Aug 2014 - Oct 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Managed large scale tech projects with hundreds of contractors to ensure delivery of assessment, A/B testing, black box testing, and crowdsourced data for search algorithms, ad relevancy, database quality assurance, and GIS mapping systems accuracy

Developed ground-up training program for multiple projects, collaborated with engineering team on the best use cases and functions of internal LMS, escalated both support and feature requests in order to improve proprietary LMS developed in coordination with Project Managers and Quality team

Created training materials such as webpages and guides, webcast videos, newsletters, online quizzes, and distributed various feedback to thousands of online vendors in order to provide data to provide search engine evaluation data to one of the largest search engines in the world

Maintained tools and self-guided LMS academies for web-based training in order to bring new and struggling contractors up to project standards

Participated in team discussions in order to effectively manage and gauge the quality of our extensive network of work-at-home contractors

Engaged in creative, out-of-the-box thinking and problem solving to come up with flexible and actionable solutions in order to achieve, enhance, and maintain quality for client standards Maintained lines of communication between team, clients, and contractors through multiple lines of web communication

Assigned and edited team-collaborated feedback and educational tools to train contractors for multiple projects



Quality Analyst

Feb 2013 - Aug 2014 (1 year 7 months)

Analyzed and interpreted quality Search Engine Evaluation guidelines in order to provide feedback and instruction for one of the biggest search engines in the world

Managed large queue of vendors, directed workflow opportunities and contractual terminations based on guidelines and project standards

Oversaw quality of projects collaboratively within a team-based context

Sent feedback to dozens of vendors weekly for various types of work within project

Created materials to train and increase quality of vendors, developed blueprints for project features to enhance communication and training ability

Answered daily questions and saw to various needs of contractors through multiple lines of communication



Editorial Intern

Jun 2012 - Sep 2012 (4 months)

Drafted correspondence between authors, editors and agents

Synthesized book matter into concise, descriptive passages to accentuate selling points

Edited study guides published online for group use

Evaluated incoming book proposals

Education



Berkeley UC Berkeley Extension

Full Stack Web Development, Computer Programming

Nov 2022 - May 2023

Learning the MERN stack in web development - MongoDB, Express JS, React, Node JS in order to create full JavaScript applications



California State University - East Bay

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), English (Creative Writing Option)

Solano Community College

Transfer Eligible, Journalism and English 2005 - 2009

Licenses & Certifications

- Berkeley Full Stack Web Development (in Progress) UC Berkeley Extension
- Business Metrics for Data-Driven Companies Coursera Course Certificates WCHGKN5NPGK8
- Mastering Data Analysis in Excel Coursera Course Certificates
 T5KCZ5BEVLK5
- Managing Big Data with MySQL Coursera Course Certificates
 YFX2KMJ425RG
- **ADDIE: Training and Development Professionals' Guide** Udemy UC-JJ0715CI
- Learning SCORM and Tin Can API Lynda.com
 D6326E789D034A84AECE10658F1713ED
- in Learning Minitab LinkedIn
- in Operational Excellence Foundations LinkedIn
- in Statistics Foundations LinkedIn
- in Leading Productive Meetings LinkedIn
- instructional Design For ELearning Udemy UC-NTDW2ONC
- in Lean Six Sigma Foundations LinkedIn
- in Six Sigma: Black Belt LinkedIn

- Adobe Captivate Essential Training LinkedIn
 AagdmAQ3toP0RNqplEfL-xINPdAc
- Programming Foundations: APIs and Web Services LinkedIn
- in Change Management Foundations LinkedIn
- in Agile Instructional Design LinkedIn
- Project Management Foundations: Teams LinkedIn
- in Project Management Foundations: Communication LinkedIn
- in Operational Excellence Work-Out and Kaizen Facilitator LinkedIn
- Lean Six Sigma: Define and Measure Tools LinkedIn
- in Becoming a Six Sigma Black Belt LinkedIn AcXlaJzQw2pwOmxushfLveEXSIZI
- Six Sigma Yellow Belt 6sigmastudy The global certification body for six sigma certifications
 738835
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) SCRUMstudy Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile
 821181
- Scrum Master Certified (SMC) SCRUMstudy Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile
 Issued Jan 2021 Expires Jan 2024
 822194
- DevOps, CI/CD(Continuous Integration/Delivery for Beginners Udemy UC-4f9c71de-32ab-40d6-8f41-cd3c034d8168
- The Complete SQL Course Udemy UC-c3bc6a83-fed6-402c-a4a8-95997c464b81/

Skills

Project Management • Technical Support • MySQL • Microsoft Excel • Tableau • MERN Stack • JavaScript • Scrum • Six Sigma • Training

Honors & Awards

First Place Critical Review - Journalism Association of Community Colleges

Highest honor for critical review awarded by the Journalism Association of Community Colleges during Arts & Entertainment Editorship at student newspaper

2012 Dean's List - CSU East Bay Academic Affairs

2012

GPA of 3.8 or higher for eligible terms